[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the purpose of the virtual DOM in React?",
    "options": ["To provide a direct interaction with the real DOM", "To improve performance by minimizing direct DOM manipulation", "To store data for React components", "To style React components"],
    "answer": "To improve performance by minimizing direct DOM manipulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What does JSX stand for?",
    "options": ["JavaScript Syntax Extension", "JavaScript Exchange", " JavaScript XML", "JavaScript X"],
    "answer": " JavaScript XML"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following methods is used to change the state of a React component?",
    "options": ["this.updateState()", "this.changeState()", "this.stateChange()", "this.setState()"],
    "answer": "this.setState()"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which of the following is a correct way to pass data from a parent to a child component in React?",
    "options": ["Using state", " Using props", "Using methods", "Using context"],
    "answer": " Using props"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What does the render() method in a React component do?",
    "options": ["It handles lifecycle events", "It triggers an API call", "It returns JSX to describe the component’s UI", "It updates the state"],
    "answer": "It returns JSX to describe the component’s UI"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "How can you handle side effects in a functional component using React hooks?",
    "options": ["Using useState", "Using useEffect", "Using useContext", "Using useReducer"],
    "answer": "Using useEffect"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "In which lifecycle method would you typically make an API call in a React class component?",
    "options": ["componentDidMount", "render", "componentWillUnmount", "shouldComponentUpdate"],
    "answer": "componentDidMount"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the primary difference between functional and class components in React?",
    "options": ["Class components do not support lifecycle methods", "Functional components can manage state", "Class components use this keyword while functional components don’t", "Functional components must always render UI"],
    "answer": "Class components use this keyword while functional components don’t"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What hook is used to manage state in a functional component?",
    "options": ["useEffect", "useContext", "useReducer", "useState"],
    "answer": "useState"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following is true about props in React?",
    "options": ["Props can only be passed from a child component to a parent component", " Props are mutable", "Props can be used to pass data from a parent to a child component", "Props are only used in functional components"],
    "answer": "Props can be used to pass data from a parent to a child component"
  }
]
